Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(AIR WHOOSHES)
Whoever gets
to the temple first wins!
What? Aang. no fair!
(BLOWS RASPBERRY. GIGGLES)
AIRBENDER 1:
Let's get him!
AIRBENDER 2:
Come on. hurry up!
(ALL GIGGLING)
(ROARS)
Hi. Nima.
Good morning. Aang.
Hey. Mip-Mip.
Oh. hello. Aang.
(GASPS)
GYATSO: Oh. perfect timing.
Huh?
(CHUCKLES)
Mind giving me a lift?
Gyatso. this isn't
the best time.
I'm getting old. you know.
(AIRBENDERS LAUGHING)
My body doesn't move
like it used to.
I'm kind of
in the middle of something.
You are so heavy!
GYATSO: Heavy? Me?
I eat nothing but vegetables.
AANG: Pie is not a vegetable.
I'm gonna lose the race!
GYATSO: Race? What race?
We finally won!
We won! We won!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yay. we did it!
Aang. as an Airbender.
it's important that you know
when to show restraint.
Even if you have
the power to win.
you are the Avatar.
A lot of people
are going to rely on you.
(ECHOES)
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(YELPS)
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING. SCREAMING)
WOMAN: Where's the Avatar?
MAN: He's gone! He ran away!
What? I'm here!
MAN: Where's the Avatar?
WOMAN: Avatar!
Aang! Where are you?
Gyatso! I'm here!
I'm... I'm... here!
I'm here! I'm here!
Here!
I'm here.
(PANTS. SIGHS)
(PURRS)
Hey. Momo.
Hi. Appa.
Was I asleep for long?
(GRUNTS)
Okay. okay.
I'm awake already.
I know. I know.
We've got a job to finish.
(SIGHS)
Let's continue our journey.
Back to our old home.
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(MOMO CHITTERS)
AANG: This may not
have been our best trip.
but any Airbender relic we find
makes it all worthwhile.
This could be the oldest piece
in our collection.
"Sonam."
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
I miss you.
(MUSIC TURNS TENSE)
Momo. go outside with Appa.
(CHITTERS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Now!
(ALL GRUNTING)
AANG: Whoa!
(JIE GRUNTS)
Who are you?
Why are you doing this?
(ALL GRUNTING)
Please stop.
I don't want to hurt you.
(KALLIK GROANS)
(YUDDAH YELLS)
HONG: Where is it?
Where is it?
No. that's not it.
(ANTIQUES SMASHING)
Hey. those are antiques.
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTS)
Enough!
HONG: Wait! I found it!
(YELPS)
Sonam? Why are they after you?
(YUDDAH GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
Wait!
No! That's a thousand years old!
(KALLIK GRUNTS)
Give it to me!
Why don't we just talk?
Maybe I can help.
We don't need your help. Avatar.
We're done living in a world
where Benders have all the power
and we have none.
Who are you?
We're the Denied.
The Denied?
JIE: Just kill him already!
YUDDAH: No! You'll bring
the whole place down!
(KALLIK GASPS)
(MUSIC SOFTENS)
(GRUNTS)
(YELPS)
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(WHIMPERS)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
You... saved me.
JIE: Kallik. grab the map.
Let's go!
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(WOOD CREAKS)
(ALL WHIMPERING)
HONG: Oh. no!
(AANG PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(WHIMPERING)
(STRUCTURE RUMBLING)
(EPIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
(APPA GRUNTS)
(CHITTERING)
(PANTING) I'm fine.
Momo. I'm fine.
(GROANING)
But we've got
to get to Republic City.
Appa. yip-yip!
KATARA: Water.
Her tribes gather strength
from the moon
and flow with the tides.
TOPH: Earth.
A kingdom of unshakable will.
reliable and strong.
(ROCKS RUMBLE)
ZUKO: Fire.
A nation capable
of great destruction.
but also of great warmth.
(FIRE WHOOSHES)
AANG: Air.
Peaceful nomads with
the power of a hurricane.
but the spirit
of a gentle breeze.
For generations. the Avatar.
the one master
of all four elements.
kept the nations in balance.
But when that responsibility
fell to me as a child.
I ran away.
I was caught in a deadly storm.
but my Avatar spirit
preserved me
in a sphere of energy
where I stayed
for a hundred years.
I woke to discover
that the balance
preserved by the Avatar
had been destroyed by war.
The Air Nomads were gone.
All but one.
Me.
I could no longer run
from my responsibility
as the Avatar.
I found allies
from every nation.
Benders and Nonbenders.
Katara taught me
how to waterbend.
Toph trained me in the ways
of the Earthbenders.
Zuko. once my worst enemy.
became my firebending teacher.
Sokka showed me that bravery
is the most important part
of being a leader.
We became a family.
And together. we ended
the Hundred Year War.
Then. we began the hard work
of rebuilding the world.
(EPIC MUSIC PLAYING)
KATARA: For so long.
the nation stood apart.
alone.
and we all suffered
as a result.
But here.
on this ancient site.
we created a place
where all people are welcome.
Bender and Nonbender alike.
working together in peace
to build the future.
Though there are still
those who would seek
to divide us.
we remain united.
As a council representative.
I am honored
to be here today
celebrating the anniversary
of Republic City
and the opening
of Unity Tower.
a symbol for all people.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Look!
Yeah!
It's the Avatar!
(CHUCKLES)
Whoo!
(BOTH GROANING)
(SIGHS)
Momo!
(CHITTERING)
(GIGGLES)
(CHUCKLES) Appa!
I missed you too.
old friend.
Aang!
Katara!
KATARA: Mm!
(KISSES)
(GROANS)
You're hurt.
(PEACEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
KATARA: Take a deep breath.
(AANG INHALES)
KATARA: And... exhale.
(AANG EXHALES)
I've heard the Denied
are growing in numbers.
but they've never
done anything like this.
Attacking the Avatar?
Yeah.
They were incredible fighters.
Even without bending.
(BACK CRACKS)
(SHOUTS)
Oops. Breathe through it.
Ow! (GROANS)
Be honest.
You're enjoying this.
Aang. this is serious.
Whatever this map
they took was.
if they were willing
to kill the Avatar to get it.
what else
are they willing to do?
I don't know.
I'm worried about you.
You're spending more
and more time
at the Air Temple. alone.
It's how I hold on to my past.
I know how hard
this is for you.
(SIGHS)
When I was attacked.
all I could think about
was that...
this could be it.
I'm the last Airbender.
If I die.
my culture dies with me.
You may be the last Airbender.
but you're not alone.
Aang. none of this
would exist without you.
You made the city possible
with your heart
and your mind.
Because of you...
all of the nations
live here...
together.
All except mine.
I know...
but the people here
still need your protection.
You're an Airbender...
but you're also the Avatar.
You're right.
Whoever this Sonam person is.
I need to find out more.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
Aang.
AANG: Avatar Roku.
ROKU: It is good
to see you again.
How can I help you?
In your lifetime.
did you ever hear
of an ancient Airbender
named Sonam?
I have not.
but you have many
past lives to call upon.
Perhaps one further back
in the Avatar cycle
can help you.
Thank you. Avatar Roku.
(VOICES WHISPERING)
I'm sorry.
I've never heard of Sonam.
I'm unfamiliar.
PAST AVATAR: Perhaps earlier.
You must go further back.
PAST AVATARS. OVERLAPPING:
Not here.
...in the Avatar Cycle.
(VOICES FADE)
AANG: Um. hello?
Is there anyone here?
Hello?
(GRUNTS)
XIAN: (IN BOOMING VOICE)
Who calls upon Avatar Xian's
vast wealth of knowledge?
(XIAN COUGHS. CLEARS THROAT)
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
Oh. hello.
You look like an Avatar
from a time
quite distant from mine.
Please. please.
tell me about your era.
What are people wearing?
Are sandals still a thing?
Uh. yes.
(SCOFFS) Why?
Why. after so many years.
open toes. seeing someone
else's crusty cuticles?
Disgusting!
Right.
Anyway. I have come
for your guidance.
You see. I was attacked.
It was not me. okay?
Wasn't me.
I know that.
I think it might have
something to do
with an Airbender named Sonam.
Hmm. Sonam.
It sounds familiar.
Sonam.
Where have I heard
that name before?
(GASPS) Ah-ha!
Sonam was the youngest daughter
of the owner
of the possum-chicken shop
at the corner marketplace.
Wait. that was my ex.
So Nyung.
If only she didn't have
those humongous toenails.
(GROANS) Disgusting.
This is going nowhere.
Sonam... So-nahm...
Sonum?
(SIGHS) Well.
thank you for your time.
I must continue my search.
Oh. Sonam!
You're asking about the legend
of the lost Avatar.
Sonam was an Avatar?
Indeed she was!
She was the Avatar
in the golden age
of Airbenders.
Legend said she had
a staff that could channel
the vast energy
of the Spirit World.
granting its keeper
unlimited power.
Is... Is that even possible?
Eh. we'll never know for sure.
Many Avatars have tried
to communicate with her.
but they couldn't.
She disappeared
so completely
that it was as if
she never existed.
And perhaps
it's better that way.
Maybe such a staff
was too dangerous
for anyone to possess.
even the Avatar.
But... But that's exactly
why I need to find it.
The people who attacked me
discovered a map.
It must lead to the staff.
Avatar Xian. please.
you have to tell me
where it is.
The legend says that Sonam
disappeared with her staff
on the peak
of Mount Baihu.
AANG: "Katara. I'm sorry
to leave so suddenly.
but I found out
what the Denied are after."
"Sonam had a staff
of immense power.
and in their hands.
it could be
a devastating weapon."
"They have a head start."
"There's no time to waste."
"You take Appa and Momo
and gather up
the rest of the team."
"We're gonna need some help."
GRAND CHAMBERLAIN:
Next on the agenda.
a Fire Nation naval vessel
came into conflict
with an extremist group
of Nonbenders called the Denied.
They've been
robbing ancient sites...
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
An urgent message has arrived
from Republic City.
How impudent.
Can't you see
Fire Lord Zuko is...
ZUKO: Chamberlain.
There's only one person
who can send a message
urgent enough to interrupt
the Fire Lord's counsel.
Is it from the Avatar?
MESSENGER: Yes. my lord.
ZUKO: Read it to me.
Yes. my lord.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Um... (CLEARS THROAT)
What are you doing?
Read it quickly.
Uh... Yeah. yeah.
Yes. Grand Chamberlain.
(CLEARS THROAT)
"Flameo Hotman.
how's ruling the Fire Nation?"
"I hope the boring Chamberlain
you mention in your letters
isn't still annoying you."
(ALL GASP)
"Anyhoo. to cut to the chase.
I need your help."
(SIGHS)
MESSENGER: "Can you please
come immediately?"
"Oh. and don't forget to bring
some firecracker buns."
(SIGHS)
SOKKA: Allow me
to present Sokka-Cycle.
Flames launch you into the sky
where you can drop
water bombs on your enemies.
then skis pop out
to help you stick the landing.
(CHUCKLES)
Pretty great. right?
Eh. boring.
Why would you need a sled
when you can just waterbend?
Ooh. ooh. ooh.
Like me. like me!
Whee!
Keep in mind.
there are still
plenty of folks like me
who can't bend.
Why would Avatar Aang
partner with a Nonbender?
(GROANS) Why?
I'll tell you why.
I saved him from the iceberg.
My boomerang flew by his side
while I parried away enemies
with my trusty blade.
I even took down the whole
Fire Nation airship armada.
And on top of all that.
I was more popular than him.
You're such a liar. Sokka.
(CHIRPING)
SOKKA:
It's from the Avatar.
Really?
That's so cool!
Wow.
Oh. so now
you think I'm cool?
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
TOPH: All right. Metalbenders.
Let's see if
any of you tenderfoots
can at least make me
use my hands.
(GRUNTS)
(METAL WHIRRING)
(UPBEAT TRIBAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(METAL CLANGS)
I'm still the greatest
Earthbender in the world!
(BIRD SCREECHES)
And I'm bored.
Master Toph.
there's a bird on your head.
And?
It looks like it has a message.
TOPH: Read.
Uh. it's from Avatar Aang.
He needs your help.
It's the Denied?
The Denied?
Where is he?
Mount Baihu.
(WIND WHISTLING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(AIR WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTS)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELPS)
(WHIMPERING)
No. no. no!
No!
(GROANS)
I love that hat.
(PANTING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(MUSIC TURNS SERENE)
(PANTS)
(TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(MUSIC SOFTENS)
(CURIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(SNOW RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(ETHEREAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Sonam?
Could that be you?
(GRUNTS)
(ICE RUMBLING AND CRACKLING)
(CRACKLING)
(AIR HISSING)
(SHOUTS)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GASPS)
(EXHALES)
(PANTING)
Who are you?
(CRACKLING)
Huh?
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING. PANTING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(ICE GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(PANTING)
(WHIMPERING)
(GASPS)
(GASPS. GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERING)
(SHOUTS)
(THUDS)
(MUSIC ENDS ABRUPTLY)
(SCREAMS)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC TURNS DRAMATIC)
(ROCK CRACKLING)
Aang!
(BOTH GRUNT)
(APPA GROANS)
(GROWLS)
(MUSIC TURNS VICTORIOUS)
Team Avatar to the rescue!
(MUSIC SOFTENS)
KATARA: Aang!
You made it!
You couldn't wait a day
before running off
to get yourself killed?
I thought you were here
looking for a staff.
Who's this guy?
(SOFT HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(MOMO CHITTERING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
An Airbender.
(PANTS)
(GROANS)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(WATER RIPPLING)
SOKKA: How did he hold up
an entire mountain?
KATARA: His chi is strong.
like nothing I've ever felt.
Hey. Avatar. you think
this guy beat your record
for longest frozen Airbender?
Yeah. How long do you think
he was in that ice?
I don't know.
His tattoos look... ancient.
He's been in there a long time.
He smells good for an old guy.
Ew.
What?
My senses tell me this guy
is pretty attractive.
Toph!
Someone else confirm.
This is serious.
What does attractive even mean?
Just give me
a straight confirmation.
Is he attractive?
He's very attractive.
AANG AND KATARA: Huh?
What? He is.
It's all in the bone structure.
MAN: No...
(BOTH GASP)
No...
No!
Whoa. whoa. whoa. Hey.
Easy. you're safe.
(HEART BEATING)
MAN: Earthbender!
AANG: No. no. no!
We're all friends here.
It's okay.
Someone woke up
on the wrong side
of the mountain.
Where is she?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Where is Avatar Sonam?
You knew Sonam?
Who are you?
I don't know how to explain it.
but you've been asleep
for a long time.
I'm the Avatar now.
I'm Aang.
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
If you're the Avatar. then...
Sonam...
Well. Sonam might be long gone.
but on the bright side.
you woke up at the perfect time.
Everyone will be amazed
to see another Airbender.
Aang's not the last one anymore.
What do you mean. last?
(GULPS)
The Air Nomads.
they've been wiped out.
There's only me.
No.
Sonam's staff.
do you have it?
It's our only hope now.
What do you mean?
I thought it was a weapon.
The staff is no weapon.
It is a gift.
With it.
Sonam was able to channel
the vast power
of the Spirit World.
It was this power that
allowed Jharana to flourish.
The greatest city in the world.
an Air Nomad utopia.
where Sonam presided
over a golden age of balance
and where I devoted my life
to serving her.
In return. she raised me up
and used her staff to give me.
a lowly Nonbender.
the power to bend the air.
I was the first.
but I would not be the last.
She filled the skies
with Airbenders.
and we flew by her side.
spreading peace
across the world.
(PANTING)
Aang? Are you okay?
Sonam used the staff
to give people airbending.
If we found it...
I could bring airbending
back to the world!
(CHUCKLES)
This is incredible!
There haven't been Airbenders
for over a hundred years!
This is everything
you ever wanted. Aang.
We could heal
the greatest atrocity
my nation committed
in the war.
This could be the final step
to rebuilding the world.
Not if the Denied
get there first.
They have the map.
Who are the Denied?
A group of violent Nonbenders.
They...
They must be after the staff
to give themselves airbending.
Then there's no time to waste.
There's only one place
it could be.
Ready your bison.
We'll need to travel
across the endless ocean.
On the other side of the world?
But there's nothing out there.
There's an island.
The journey will not be easy.
But we can make it.
Then let's get going.
(CHUCKLES)
The skies are no place
for a water child.
Water child?
Um. I know you just woke up
after thousands of years.
but we do
these things together.
Trust me.
We're stronger this way.
Welcome to Team Avatar.
What's your name?
Tagah.
My name is Tagah.
Just think of it
as a big metal air bison.
TAGAH: We will travel
ancient paths through the sky.
Ones that our people learned
by following
the great air bison herds
that long ago
taught us airbending.
Air currents known only to us.
encircling the great sphere
of existence.
allowing us to travel
where we wish.
giving us our name.
the Air Nomads.
(KATARA GASPS)
(MAJESTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
ZUKO: What's he doing?
He's really feeling that air.
He's navigating by instinct.
What if his instincts
are just wrong?
Who needs instincts
when you've got
muscles like that?
Or what if
his brain is messed up
from being frozen?
Like me?
Uh. no. no!
He was frozen for
five thousand years. okay?
You were frozen for.
what. a hundred?
Okay. that's nothing.
Your brain is...
fresh.
Maybe he is
a little old-fashioned.
but look at him.
He's so in tune
with his element.
he can travel
across the entire ocean
with no map.
no instruments.
(EXHALES)
There's so much
I can learn from him.
(SNORING)
(APPA PURRING)
(CHUCKLES)
I'd give anything to be able
to see my air bison again.
(GROWLS)
And now.
to see only one remains.
Aang. you said our people
were wiped out.
yet you survived.
How?
I had just found out
I was the Avatar.
But the responsibility.
it was too much.
So I ran away.
And while I was gone.
the Fire Nation attacked.
They were looking for me.
If...
If I'd just been there.
TAGAH: Sonam would say.
Air Nomads are formed
from the mist.
We walk the world
for a moment in time.
then we return
to the eternal wind.
Monk Gyatso taught me that.
We carry the same weight.
a grief no one else
could possibly comprehend.
But you and I
can heal the past.
Let me show you how powerful
our element can be
when Airbenders work together.
Tagah. what are you doing?
Whoa!
This is how Sonam taught me.
Feel the energy that tethers us.
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
(GROWLS PLAYFULLY)
(LAUGHS)
TAGAH: The bond between us.
Can you feel it?
Use it!
This is amazing!
Yeah! (LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
Woo-hoo!
Oh. yeah!
Human boomerang!
He's actually flying.
TOPH: So are we.
Whoa. that's my best friend!
That's my best friend!
Now you throw me!
(GRUNTING)
(EPIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
I had no idea
this was possible!
This is only the beginning.
AANG: I can't believe it.
Airbenders will fill
the sky again.
TAGAH: We have been
given a great gift.
The chance to redeem ourselves.
You were destined to find me
on that mountain. Aang.
How did you end up there?
The Earthbenders
had attacked Jharana.
Sonam and I fought fearlessly.
side by side.
We drove them
back to Mount Baihu.
and that's the last
I remember.
She must have saved your life.
Only an Avatar could have
put you in that sphere.
Aang. can I ask you something?
Of course.
If the Fire Nation
destroyed the Air Nomads...
how can you suffer
the presence of the Fire Lord?
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
Zuko is a friend and an ally.
He turned against
his own father
to help me end the war.
Yet he wears
the crown himself now.
Fire by its nature burns. Aang.
Our kind have always
suffered at the hands
of the other elements.
That's why
we built Republic City.
To show the world that
if we listen to each other.
we can all live
together in peace.
(MUSIC TURNS HOPEFUL)
And once
we bring back Airbenders.
it'll be complete.
When everyone stuck
to their own.
the whole world
was nearly torn apart.
And besides. Katara.
Sokka. Zuko. Toph...
they're my family now.
I want to live in a world
where we can all be together.
You remind me so much of Sonam.
KALLIK: It's the Avatar.
And this time he's got
his friends with him.
That's the Fire Lord's airship!
How'd they get ahead of us?
They don't even have the map!
We can't risk him
getting to the staff first.
Kill him.
But he spared our lives.
And how many countless were
killed in the hundred years
waiting for his return?
Where was he when
your family was wiped out?
If we want anything to change.
we need what
the Benders have... Power.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Fire!
(BOTH GRUNT)
(AIR WHOOSHING)
(METALLIC CLANGING)
It's the Denied!
Uh. we are definitely
under attack!
Tear them to shreds!
(AIR HISSING)
(CLANKING)
Is he crushing the ship?
Tagah?
Tagah. stop!
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(ALL GRUNT)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
We're here.
The Immortal Storm.
Oh. no.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(TORNADOS ROARING)
There has to be
another way around.
No!
Together. you and I
can clear a path for the ship.
But we have to go now.
Aang. trust me.
(MOMO SCREECHES)
(APPA MOANS)
Uh. maybe now's
a good time to turn back.
ZUKO: I don't think
that's an option anymore.
Where are they going?
(ALL GRUNT)
(AIR HISSING)
The engine's out.
We're losing air pressure.
ALL: Whoa!
Katara. Toph. come with me.
What about me?
Take the wheel.
What? No. I've only ever
crashed Fire Nation airships.
Okay. let's see.
Here's our rudder.
this is the elevator.
there's our ballast.
and there's the giant tornado
that's going to kill us all.
(GRUNTS)
Follow my lead.
(MUSIC SOFTENS)
(GASPS. STRAINS)
Work with me.
just like I showed you.
We can harness the air.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(WHOOSHES)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
Yes! That's it. Aang!
Keep going!
ZUKO: There's a long tear
above your head on the left.
Got it!
ZUKO: Whatever happens.
you have to hold
the ship together.
SOKKA: Zuko! Zuko!
Aang and Tagah
are destroying tornadoes.
but there's too many.
and they're everywhere!
Just steer the ship.
Don't lose Aang.
It's not that easy.
especially when
everything is sideways.
Okay. left!
(PANTING)
(METAL CREAKS)
(LAUGHS) I did it!
(YELPS) Right!
Oh. no!
We're falling behind!
I'm losing sight of them!
We have to go back!
Trust in your friends.
They won't make it
if we don't clear a path.
(WHOOSHES)
(METAL CREAKS)
Zuko! We're gonna
crash into the sea!
When I give you the signal.
pull the lever
next to the wheel.
(RATTLING)
SOKKA:
We're gonna crash!
Katara?
(GRUNTS)
(EPIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMS)
Give me the signal!
It's closed!
Sokka. now!
Here we go!
(GRUNTS)
(MUSIC FADES)
AANG: Katara! We did it!
What were you thinking?
I was clearing the tornadoes
to make a path.
The ship almost crashed. Aang.
We could have died.
(DARK PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
And what if you
got yourself killed?
You're the Avatar.
This is too risky.
We need to turn back now.
No! We're almost there.
We just need to get
to the eye of the storm.
Aang. no.
This is too dangerous.
The staff is out there.
The Denied are after it.
Do you really believe
that they could make it
through the storm?
We're nearly there.
That staff
can bring back my people.
I understand how much
you want that. but...
You don't understand.
None of you do.
Aang...
We push forward.
TAGAH:
If we generate enough air.
we can push our way through.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(MUSIC BUILDS DRAMATICALLY)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(ALL YELP)
(MUSIC FADES)
(PANTING)
We're alive?
We made it through.
Thank you. Tagah.
It was you. Aang.
We're here because of you.
Yeah. we're having
a good time. too.
You could have told us
we were flying into
the Immortal Storm.
I know it was dangerous.
but we had to risk it.
We? (CHUCKLES)
I don't remember when
we took a vote on that.
There wasn't time.
I had to make a call.
TAGAH: Friends. please.
don't blame Aang.
This is all my fault.
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
I knew this would be difficult.
But Aang believed
in your strength as a team.
And I'm honored
to be a part of it.
I forgive you. Tagah.
AANG: Everyone. look.
These islands.
they were Lion Turtles.
Whoa.
KATARA: It's beautiful.
(BIRDS CAWING)
Long before my time.
the Lion Turtles
granted the gift
of bending to humans.
These are their final
resting grounds.
This is where Sonam came
to learn their ways.
I am certain that
she left her staff here.
Where should we start looking?
Aang. you must
connect with her.
But no one
can connect with Sonam.
TAGAH: The spiritual power
of the Lion Turtles
is still
concentrated here.
Let it guide you.
We'll set out immediately.
Actually. Tagah.
we could really
use your help here.
If the Denied are close behind.
we need to be ready.
Yeah. and we're gonna need more
than Toph's metal bending
to fix this ship.
My bending got us
through that storm.
What did you do?
Steered with his feet.
Repairs can wait.
Aang needs me.
Tagah. please.
stay and help my friends.
I'll be okay on my own.
As you wish.
We will begin repairs
for our voyage home.
AANG: Everyone. I know
I've asked a lot of you
on this journey.
but we're about
to accomplish something
that will change the world.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(APPA GROWLING)
(CAWING)
Let it guide you.
Sonam?
Oh. this is turning out to be
a nice little vacation. (SIGHS)
Aside from all the people
trying to kill us.
And the tornadoes.
Um. we're supposed
to be fixing the ship?
SOKKA:
You're doing great. buddy.
(GROANS)
KATARA: Has anyone seen Tagah?
Yes. we've all seen Tagah.
He's so gorgeous.
Jeez. I get it.
Oh. I see what you mean.
He wandered off that way.
No. maybe that way?
KATARA: Tagah!
Where are you going?
Aang needs to be protected.
I agree.
I know my ways
may seem unusual to you.
but I assure you.
everything I do.
I do for Aang.
For Aang?
Or for the staff?
You have no idea
all that we've lost.
You've never known
a world with Airbenders.
I know Aang.
He may be the last of his kind.
but he's the reason
this world knows peace.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
His values as an Air Nomad
have brought balance to chaos.
It's because of Aang
that the Water Tribes.
Earth Kingdom. and Fire Nation
now work together.
striving for harmony.
a peace we once
thought unattainable.
TAGAH: You speak of peace.
There will never be peace
among the elements.
There never was.
Your precious Republic City
is built on lies.
KATARA:
It's built on hope.
Do you have hope. Tagah?
Saving my people requires
more than just hope.
It requires sacrifice.
I saw you try to crush
the Denied's airships.
You were ready to kill them.
I know what kind
of Airbender Aang is...
but what kind
of Airbender are you?
(AIR WHOOSHING)
(RUMBLING)
TAGAH: Aang did well
getting us here.
There is great strength in him.
but weakness as well.
Weakness?
TAGAH: Yes.
You.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(ICE CRACKLING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
What the hog monkey?
No!
(GLOWING LIGHT HUMMING)
(TWINKLING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
He trusted you!
(GRUNTS)
No.
(ICE CRACKLING)
ZUKO: You traitor!
(BOOMERANG WHOOSHING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(SHOUTS)
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
Tagah!
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(AIR WHOOSHING)
(MUSIC SOFTENS)
TAGAH: Brother.
Tagah. It's real.
We can finally
bring back airbending.
Let's go tell the others.
We can do this.
Me and you.
I can't do this
without my friends.
Earth killed my people.
Fire killed yours.
The staff is the only way
we can create a new Air Empire.
One capable of defending itself.
No.
We can build
a new future. Tagah.
But it has to be for everyone.
The staff doesn't
belong to everyone.
It belongs to us.
What...
What have you done?
TAGAH: As long as they were
around. you'd always put them
ahead of our people.
Don't you see?
This is how we redeem ourselves.
It doesn't matter
that you ran then.
As long as you stand
with me now.
No... Katara.
TAGAH: Aang. listen to me.
This is the only way.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHOUTS)
You're a traitor to your own.
Just like Sonam.
(SHOUTS)
(GRUNTS)
(APPA ROARS)
(SHOUTS)
(MUSIC ENDS ABRUPTLY)
(GROANS)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(APPA MOANING)
TAGAH: I wanted to do this
with you by my side.
But if I must build
the new Air Empire alone...
so be it.
(MOANS)
There's no way in!
We have to turn back!
(STRAINING)
No! We keep trying
to push through!
Sonam's staff.
TAGAH: Denied...
the Avatar is dead.
If you wish to build a new world
where you have the power.
I can give it to you.
(MUSIC FADES)
(AANG GRUNTS)
Appa!
Katara!
Katara! (ECHOES)
Katara.
They're gone.
It's all my fault.
It's always been my fault.
Ever since I ran away.
SONAM: No Avatar has ever
fallen into such shame
as to join me
here in my sorrow.
Why do you grieve so. friend?
Avatar Sonam?
Tagah murdered my friends.
And now he has the staff.
Tagah? No.
No. I... I stopped him.
I hid the staff.
What have you done?
You're the one
who gave him airbending!
How could you give power
to a monster?
The Tagah I gave bending to
was a different man.
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
SONAM:
It was a different time.
The Airbenders were
the peacekeepers
of the four elements.
We used our power
to mediate all conflict
with non-violence.
But we were
the fewest in numbers.
For many years. we existed
in a beautiful balance
of great prosperity.
But the world began to shift.
The Earthbenders
formed their own kingdom.
separating from
the other elemental tribes.
The balance of the world
was at risk.
It was my duty to act.
So I learned how
to channel the energy
of the Spirit World
just as the Lion Turtles did.
To give people
the power of airbending.
My most devout pupil.
Tagah. was the first
to receive it.
I sent my new peacekeepers out
to help calm
the growing unrest.
But they were not prepared
for the brutality
of the new Earth Kingdom.
(SCREAMS)
Tagah watched
as his brothers and sisters
were all slaughtered.
His heart darkened
by the violence of war.
He now saw everyone
who wasn't an Air Nomad
as the enemy.
Tagah begged me to use
the staff to create an army
and to kill
all who would do us harm.
I refused.
So he stole it.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
SONAM:
When he connected the staff
to the temple.
his energy was so corrupted
by grief and rage
that the power
of the Spirit World
(TAGAH SCREAMS)
consumed him.
Tagah became something
more than human.
too powerful to kill.
It took all my energy
to finally trap him
high above the clouds.
where no one would find him.
I reclaimed the staff.
but I was fatally wounded.
Before the Earth Kingdom
could invade Jharana.
I sent the remaining Air Nomads
into the mountains.
And I hid my temple
in the Spirit World.
where no one
could access its power.
Then I locked the staff away.
where only the Avatar
could find it.
I died. hoping that one day.
another Avatar would
create more Airbenders
and restore balance
to this world.
And that Avatar is you. Aang.
You have to get my staff
before Tagah connects it
to the temple.
There's still time.
Don't let my regret
become yours.
AANG: My friends and I
fought hard for this peace.
I won't let him
start another war.
Help me find a way back.
(MUSIC BUILDS
THEN STOPS ABRUPTLY)
AANG: Sonam?
What's happening?
(YELPS)
No!
No! Please!
I have to fix this!
This can't be it!
I can't die yet!
Please! Not yet!
No!
KATARA: Aang?
Katara?
KATARA: I'm losing him.
Come on. Aang!
Come on! Aang!
Hold on!
(GASPS)
Aang!
Katara!
I was so worried.
SOKKA: Aang!
AANG: Sokka!
(SOKKA SIGHS)
I knew you'd
pull through. buddy.
Hey. Aang.
Zuko!
(CHITTERS)
Momo!
Welcome back. twinkle toes.
Toph. you're okay.
I...
I thought you were all dead.
We were.
But Katara saved us.
The spiritual power
of these waters
strengthened my healing abilities.
You're incredible. Katara.
Where's Appa?
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
Tagah must have taken him.
I'm sorry.
No.
I can't believe I trusted him.
KATARA:
We'll get through this.
SOKKA:
So. let me get this straight.
He's pulling Sonam's temple
out of the Spirit World
to gain unlimited power.
and let me guess.
you want us to stop him?
Sure. only problem
is your air bro
crushed our ship
and stole your bison.
Also. there's a massive
typhoon surrounding us!
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
I don't say this very often.
but Sokka's right.
Thank you.
Yep. we're stuck.
And there aren't
enough Lion Turtles
for all of us
to have our own island.
so I'm calling this one.
I'm naming him Snappy.
SOKKA: Aw.
Snappy is the best one.
TOPH: I know.
We may not know where Tagah is.
but we know
what he's looking for
is in the Spirit World.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
And lucky for us.
we're stuck in the most
spiritually charged place
on the planet.
So I may be able to open
a portal to get us there.
if I can summon an old friend.
(ALL YELP)
Wow.
ZUKO: The ocean spirit.
(MUSIC TURNS EPIC)
(GROWLS)
This portal smells an awful lot
like the fish market.
I'm gonna go check on Snappy.
Face your death with honor.
I'm sorry.
I know I got us into this.
but I promise you
I'll fix it.
KATARA: We'll fix it...
together.
SOKKA:
We're gonna die!
Woah!
(SOKKA GROANS)
What?
Where's my power pony?
Uh. were my hands
always this small?
(YELPS) It's Baby Toph!
Baby Toph!
(GRUNTING)
What the hog monkey?
(YELPS) Old people!
Gran Gran?
It's your sister.
you meathead!
Give me Toph.
There. there. Toph.
Oh. no. Zuko!
What happened
to your beautiful face?
You look like a dried sea squid.
(GROANS)
No. Zuko!
Tired.
Ow. ow. ow!
What's going on here?
AANG: The Spirit World
is out of balance.
And so are we.
That's gotta be Tagah.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
AANG: Oh. no!
He's pulling Sonam's temple
into our world!
We're running out of time!
GORILLAVARK: (YELLING) Chunder!
(ALL YELP)
(SIGHS) Pretty good landing.
(GROANS)
Whoa! Humans!
I love humans!
Two brothers.
their little sister.
and an elderly couple.
ZUKO AND KATARA: A couple?
Not a couple!
Whoa! Looks like
I touched a nerve.
Oh. look at this one.
Hello. Ow!
Toph. no! Bad Toph.
We don't bite strangers.
(YELPS)
AANG: Great Spirit. excuse me.
Did you just come from
that temple in the sky?
I certainly did.
It was my favorite hidey-hole
until that dark.
yucky energy started
corrupting this whole place.
Please. we need your help
getting up there.
It's my duty to stop this.
I'm the Avatar.
(CHITTERS)
Ooh. the Avatar.
Let me have a squiz at you.
Okay. Now with this eye.
And this eye.
Mm-hmm. And this eye.
Don't forget this eye.
Hey. hey. can we hurry up?
GORILLAVARK: Every eye needs
to have a squiz!
Sniff check!
(YELPING)
Ooh. that's Avatar material
right there.
Yes. it is. Oh!
Yes. yes. yes. yes. yes.
It appears the universe
has brought us together
for a very important mission...
Ah?
...to flee!
Run for your lives!
Wait. come back!
You're going the wrong way!
Stop!
Please. Great Spirit.
both of our worlds
are in danger!
No. no. no. no. no. no.
I am not going back up there.
(GASPS)
(CHITTERS)
Hmm. Well. when you
put it like that.
it does make more sense.
Upon reflection.
I've decided I shall help you
and your human-y friends.
What did he say?
Nice work. Momo.
All right. in you go.
By the way.
no eating anything you find
in my teeth. as I'm
saving that for later.
Ready. set. get steady and ret.
One and a two
and a you know what to do.
Blast off!
(ALL SHOUTING)
I know we haven't known
each other very long. but...
I love you!
You don't have to say it back.
(ALL GRUNT)
Hey! You got your hair back!
Why are my eyes teary?
Was I crying?
No way! Look!
What?
What is it?
AANG: It's Republic City.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
We can't let him destroy
everything we built!
We won't.
(CLAMORING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
Boomerang!
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Give me the staff. Tagah!
I see I underestimated you.
Avatar.
Your friends are stronger
than I thought.
But you're too late.
(ALL SHOUTING)
The Denied.
You see?
I did what you wanted. Aang.
I returned airbending
to the world.
(CHUCKLES)
What's the plan?
We'll deal with the Denied.
You have to get the staff.
I will rebuild Jharana
on the ruins of our enemies.
just as they did on ours.
A new Air Empire will rise.
Kill them all.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(WHIMPERING)
We have to get
these people out of here.
(SHOUTS)
(GROANS. GASPS)
Oh. yeah!
AANG: Tagah!
Give it to me!
This isn't the way!
We can use the staff
to bring back balance. peace!
You care so much
about your ideals
that you let
your people die!
I will do anything
to make sure they survive!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(CLAMORING)
(GROWLS)
(SCREECHING)
My cabbages!
Not my cabbages!
(SCREAMS)
(SNIFFLES) My cabbages!
My cabbages!
(YELLS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
Don't do this.
You have the power now.
You can decide how to use it.
I'm not like you.
The world hasn't
been good to me.
The world is what we make it.
JIE: Get away from her!
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
Tagah. stop!
(SHOUTS)
You betrayed me!
You betrayed our culture!
I gave you every chance
to see the truth!
Shouldn't you be
in the Fire Nation?
I'm fighting for the peace
of all nations!
Big talk from someone
who sits on a throne
built on a century of war!
(ROCKS RUMBLING)
(METAL CREAKING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
I'm still the greatest
Earthbender in the world!
(BLADE DINGS)
(AIR WHISTLES)
(BOTH GRUNT)
Oh. no.
I'm out of water.
(CACKLES) We got ya!
And there's no Avatar
here to save you.
SOKKA: Sokka-Cycle!
Huh?
(BELL DINGING)
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
Let's see if
your fancy new bending
can beat some good old
nonbending know-how.
(GROANING)
SOKKA: Bombs away!
(DENIED MEMBERS GRUNTING)
You just got denied!
Whoa!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
(ALL COUGHING)
Let's go!
Good luck saving your city.
Huh?
(GASPS)
(CITIZENS SCREAMING)
We have to save
as many people as we can.
(CITIZEN YELPS. PANTS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(GASPS)
AANG: I know your pain.
I know what you've been through.
You don't know.
I watched as all of my brothers
and sisters were slaughtered.
When the Fire Nation
burned the Air Nomads to ash.
where were you?
You ran!
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
Tagah!
No!
(MUSIC ENDS ABRUPTLY)
(WHOOSHES)
(CITIZENS CLAMORING)
The full power
of the Spirit World
flows through me!
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
This is what strength
looks like!
(SHOUTS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(GASPS)
(SHUDDERED BREATHING)
(CLAMORING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
You should've run away
like you did
all those years ago.
little Avatar.
I...
won't run.
Then at least you'll die
knowing you're not
the last Airbender!
(GASPS)
(SHOUTS)
TAGAH: Aang!
No!
(SHOUTS)
(CLAMORING)
(ROARS)
(CHITTERS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
No.
(CHIMING)
(CLATTERING)
(SHOUTS)
(GRUNTS)
We could've been brothers!
We could've done this together!
It didn't have to end like this!
It's Aang!
He's got the staff!
Yeah!
Kick his butt. Mega Aang!
No! Something's wrong!
The power is corrupting him!
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
AANG: I dreamt of bringing
the Air Nomads back
to the world
as peacekeepers.
They could have been
a beacon of light
for the world to follow.
But you ruined it!
You twisted my dream
into a nightmare!
Finally. you have the power
the Air Nomads need.
Maybe there is hope
for you after all.
(GRUMBLES)
(SHOUTING)
(SCREAMS)
Do it!
Use the staff!
Show me you have the strength
to bring our people back!
Do it!
(SHOUTING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC STOPS ABRUPTLY)
(PEACEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
(LAUGHS)
GYATSO: Aang.
You will do so many great things
as the Avatar.
but you must be prepared
to do what frightens you
the most.
Your people. your home.
we are always with you.
(GROANING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
No.
No!
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHOUTS)
(BOTH WHIMPER)
(GASPS)
No! My power!
No.
No!
(GROANS. PANTS)
You fool!
Why?
Why did you break it?
We could have fixed everything.
We can't erase
the pain of the past.
We couldn't save them.
But it's our duty
to protect our people.
Not at the cost of betraying
everything they stood for.
No.
It's time to let go.
You have to forgive yourself.
I have to forgive myself too.
Air nomads are formed
from the mist.
BOTH: We walk the world
for a moment in time.
Then we return
to the eternal wind.
(GROWLS)
(GASPS) Aang!
Hey. Katara.
Hey. Aang.
Seriously?
You do realize
you're falling. right?
Hey. if you ever get tired
of relying on Appa.
I could hook you up
with one of these babies.
(WHIMPERING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
SOKKA: I'll give you
the best friend discount!
(CHATTERING)
These are pretty good!
AANG: I don't know
if airbending will ever return.
but I know now
that the true power
of the Air Nomads
was never their bending.
It was their values.
And that's a power
I can pass on to others.
Avatar Aang. you are
the true embodiment
of the Air Nomads.
Thank you for giving up
the power that I could not.
You give me hope for the future
of our culture.
(EPIC ETHEREAL MUSIC PLAYING)
It's amazing. isn't it?
The first new air temple
in centuries.
Republic City
is finally complete.
A city for all nations.
just like you promised.
I never could have done this
without you. Katara.
Hey. everybody.
Sorry I kept you all waiting.
Are you ready for our big trip?
As my new acolytes. you'll be
helping me preserve our culture
for future generations.
So. who wants
to search for artifacts
at an ancient
abandoned temple?
(FLATLY) Yay.
I'm only going
to make sure you don't try
to release another
beefy old Airbender.
Yeah. I'm done
with bad boys.
AANG: Avatar Sonam told me
about this place.
So it's very possible
that no one's been here
in hundreds of years.
Oh! Is this
an Airbender relic?
I think that's just a rock.
But I love the enthusiasm.
(CHIRPS)
Aw!
(ROARS)
(YELPS)
AANG: Keep your eyes open.
You never know what
we might discover here.
Woah!
I thought they were extinct.
(ROARS)
I can't believe it.
The original Airbenders.
Aw. can I have one?
(LAUGHS)
Appa. yip yip!
(PEACEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm